# **Jatin Grover**

#### Sr. Frontend Developer

Versatile Developer with 6+ years of experience in various technologies such as Web Development, Data Analytics and developing Microservices. Mostly prominent in ReactJS, Redux, TypeScript and Python as primary languages to create high-end WebApps, along with good ability to create Reporting Dashboards.

groverjatin17@gmail.com

Toronto, Canada

in linkedin.com/in/groverjatin17

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Sr. Frontend Developer** Sunlife - (IT Frog)

01/2023 - Present

Toronto, CA

Achievements/Tasks

- Using TypeScript/ReactJs/JavaScript to develop designs from Figma or Adobe XD and connecting the Front end interface with the backend Microservices.
- Working with Sunlife eCommerce project to further extend their line of products. It involves using react-hook-forms, styled-components, lefthook amongst many libraries. The app supports pickup as well as delivery orders.
- Fetching data from a APIs, wrangling the response and render them onto variety of front-end designs. Storing the data onto Global State Management tool i.e. Redux or React-Context.
- End to end testing of the entire product using RTL, Jest or Enzyme. Putting test-driven development first and writing custom test functions
- Discussion with team over the analysis, design and development aspects of the project in Scrum meetings.

# Frontend Developer Amdocs

11/2019 - 04/2021

Pune. IN

Achievements/Tasks

- Implementing high fidelity designs into interactive webapps.
   Using HTML5, CSS, SASS on daily basis.
- Built CSR interface for Cellcom(Israel) where the user account information, interactions, services were tracked. This involved making changes to existing plans of the customer.
- Worked in Vodafone(Italy) where the team built the entire Vodafone's web portal where customer can buy plans, phones, edit information, add items to shopping cart etc.
- Developed REST APIs from scratch using Node. Js and Express. Js as primary technologies although at times Spring boot MVC architecture was used.
- Collaboration with product team members to implement new feature developments as per given wireframes.
- Using Nodemailer, StripeJS, Mongoose, jwtoken and other libraries to add mailing, payment and security features in the backend.
- Regular feature development, bugfixes, maintaining existing codebase and approving PRs.

437-984-8059

jatingrover.net/

github.com/groverjatin17

### **SKILLS**



### **EDUCATION**

# **Reporting and Database Management**Conestoga College

01/2022 - 08/2022

# **Computer Application Developer** Conestoga College

05/2021 - 12/2021

# **Bachelor in Computer Science** Chitkara University

07/2013 - 07/2017

#### PET PROJECTS

#### World of Ortho

- A responsive, multilingual website for Ortho hospital where patients can book an appointment with the respective Doctor
- https://world-of-ortho.com/

#### Toronto Mobile Flooring

- A website for a flooring company that sells Canadian Hardwood, Vinyl, Tiles and Laminate. They are prominent company for flooring and renovation.
- http://torontomobileflooring.com/

#### **INTERESTS**

Mixed Martial Arts Backpacking Reading

Punjabi Folk Dance Cycling

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Develoepr** Standard Chartered

06/2017 - 11/2019

Bangalore, IN

Achievements/Tasks

- Custom Web Application for employees within SC Bank to find relevant skilled colleagues to seek guidance in their projects. Other than that developers can ask questions from fellow developers pertaining to their codebase.
- The webapp used External APIs from GitHub and Stack Overflow to verify the skill level of the developer. Along with self review and public review of developer's skills.
- This tech stack of the portal was based on ReactJS, Java/Spring Boot, SQL and Linux based VM for deployment.